Preliminary guide to the Elizabeth "Betita" Sutherland Martínez papers M1854
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 2. Activism: Miscellaneous
  - M-L material, Spanish. Labor-U.S. General, Latin America- General (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - M-L documents (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Translating sources II. Nacs + males (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - 1999 Toyota. Males-8/18/95. Nacs 3/26/95 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Bakke Decision (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Lulac, Progressive movement - clippings, fliers etc. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Islee, General 1987, Go Board meetings (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - U.S mixed unsorted (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Solidarity Bolivia, Anti-war, Self portrait, Workers daily life, Vanguard-10th anniversary, Cultural workers (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Nica mobilizations, Alfbetizpelon, El Salvador solidarity, Earthquake solidarity in U.S. 1985-86, the boarder (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Anti-intervention picture booklet (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Las Tumbas Franciscas, Punto Critico, motive, Must we choose sides, Solidarity with Nacozari copper miners (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - United Airlines strike, Post office strike, Arizona farmworkers, '77, '81, '83 farmworkers, 1977 Bakke (or 1978), Chile portfolio, Nacazaro miners (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - U.S. rural south, Asian Americans, Women issues, Africa (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Good Guys 1945-, General U.S political figures, personalities (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bad guys before 1945, Bad guys 1945-, Good guys before 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - World history before 1945, World history 1945-, U.S. labor history 1945- (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - U.S. political history before 1900, U.S. Political History 1945- (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - U.S. political/labour history 1900-1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Levi's flyers, U.S labour history before 1900 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Levi's flyers, etc. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - F.C panel, Levi Strauss letter, Hispanics, 1992-11-11 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chicano movement contacts 1990's, 1960's film music, Freedom socialist newspapers (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - James Anderson (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Nomination packets for youth together (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annete James, Flor Cristomo, Sally, Marta Fuentes, Nancy Cook (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Discussions series, Advisory board, Mondo bio/photos, Eric Lozano, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Linda Evans, Susan Jones, Tony Platt (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nebraska state prison, Rod Bush book visit, End to white supremacy, Mike Davis, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mondo (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Royal Jones, Mothers of East L.A. prisoners letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Richard Jackson, Efren Pardes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Catalyst product, Maria E. Ramirez, Jason Ferrera (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Antonio Cordora 1971-72. Riro Killing (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Books about the 60's (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Social activism, legacy of the 1960's (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Prison letters, articles, flyers, etc. (Box 1, Folders 1-2)
- 3. Activism: women/feminism
  - Feminism, Correspondence, Cleaver defense 4/68 (Box 165, Folder 1)
  - Women newsclippings (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Womens studies international forum, womens study group (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Women, Global feminism, Sexism current (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Latina women health, Male view of events, Feminism in U.S., Raza students + sexism (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - New women struggle introduction (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Women's Foundation info, 1992 proposals (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Socialist Feminist conference,Themes: womanism, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Chicanas article for adelaids, Alpert- 1, Women and health/ mental health, women and law, Herstory (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Reagan speech, Contemporary Latina literature (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Left wing anti-feminism, Women-other countries, Current clippings- Latin America. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 3rd world women (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Women M-L writings, Women as workers (Box 34, Folder 4)
- 4. Activism: SNCC /1960s Civil Rights/Mississippi
  - Cuba report-Bill Johnson documents collected in Mississippi July 5-12 1964 (Flat-box 177, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook of memories sweet and sour, Lesson to recognize the importance of rhythm (Flat-box 174, Folder 2)
  - SNCC literature, clippings (Flat-box 174, Folder 1)
  - What is SNCC, Wavelano, 1964-11 (Flat-box 176, Folder 1)
  - Kingston Spring SNCC staff meeting Executive Committee meeting, 1966-05 (Flat-box 171, Folder 2)
  - Staff meeting-Atlanta Georgia SNCC, 1969-02 (Flat-box 171, Folder 1)
  - May 1967 staff meeting, December 1966 Peg Leg Bates (Flat-box 176, Folder 3)
  - Two triple-o is here, Vietnam, SNCC, FBI 1982-3 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Modern times 10/02, Preface, Letters from Mississippi Volunteers bios, Mississippi reunion 1994 (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - SNCC- General info, Rob Williams Monroe, NC, 1961-1964 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - South, including Birmingham church, 1961-1963 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - My fem/SNCC, 1965 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - SNCC, The Student Voice, Aframerican report, Perspective: on Atlanta rebellion, SNCC freedom singers, Our folktales, Black Sam, The movement (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - SNCC audio, fact sheet, etc., Negroes in American History, The Silent Slaughter, Student Voice (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - SNCC years-General Climate (Box 73, Folders 1-2, Box 72, Folder 3)
  - SNCC Mississippi papers, Newsclippings, Lao (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - SNCC literature (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - The Delta Ministry, Freedom Premier, News clippings, Newsweek (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - SNCC papers, Students workings, Newsclippings (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - SNCC key documents (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - SNCC (part 1) 1965-1967. (Box 67, Folders 3-4)
  - The people make history, SNCC staff and finances (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Analysis of LNS (Terry Cannon) + New Left Items, SNCC photos (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings on Mississippi eyewitness, Newsweek, W.E.B Dubois pamphlet (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - 60's general, Mississippi Burning & movies on topic, 1968 letter mixed (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Mississippi 1964 with notebooks, newsclippings, SNCC, High tide of black resistance (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Project South, SNCC reunion (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Smith Collex, Faviana, SNCC anthology (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mississippi Reunion, 1989 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Events from Mississippi (Box 189, Folder 22)
- 5. Activism: Chicano/Latino, immigration, farmworkers, etc.
  - Spanam, Emilio Zapata (Flat-box 181, Folder 1)
  - FW; Huerta, National Institute For Latino Policy, Ethnic studies, Nike, etc. (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Labor, Fuerza unidas, 1997-1998 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Latinos: history, Lideres campesinas (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Public education, INS murder-Arizona, Dislocated workers general (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico, 2000 census, Mixed race, Latino/population (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Four directions-Claudia wedding 8/5/95, Education-bilingual, California Latino civil rights network, Chicanos in N.Y + Latinos (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Latino-Bay Area + California Terminology, Oct. 12 1996 march on Washington, D.C., Culture (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Latinos-general (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Migrants rights-AZ, Dreams act, Immigration 06-09, Immigration, women (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - Immigration rights (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - Immigration, 1996 (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Zoe Baird-1993, immigration, Network news, Latinos and Mexico, Media packet (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Latinos in the media (Box 152, Folder 3)
  - El Centro de la Raza. CMEC. Latinos: general (Box 152, Folders 1-2)
  - Chicano Moratorium Committee-Bay Area, Latinos + war (Box 151, Folder 4)
  - Zapatismo 2001-2, Close the SOA and vieques, SOA watch history, Palestine (Box 150, Folder 4)
  - San Antonio, Strategy-2003, imperialism, CA election 09, Latino Politics, Latin America, Mexico, Venezuela (Box 150, Folder 2)
  - Zapatista solidarity, Socialism conference, SOA anti-oppression/POC, SOA article (Box 149, Folder 4)
  - Labor + immigration 2000-01, Human rights, Cuba, Prisoners rights, Prisoners, Mum, Feltier (Box 149, Folder 1)
  - PCUN, Seinfeld nada, Brown Berets, Rethinking the U.S. in "paradise", Hispanics in the United States and Puerto Rico, New federalism, Betraying the young, TV news in the red and brown, PEG (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Mother Jones, Roots of empowerment, Housing divided, Be down with the brown, Miscellanous: chicano + the military MAI, Latinos, General (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - New Mexico (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Latino articles (Box 146, Folder 3)
  - Immigration, Texas (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Immigration, 1993 (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - Immigration law, Economy, Riverside beating, 1990 (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Immigration, Bay Area committee on immigration critique, Latino coalition, Borders, 1997 (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - Tejas newspaper, Immigration, 1992 (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Media, Latinos, Social issues (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Festiva latina, Latinos: youth General, Latinos-theory, Aruna-U.C. Documents (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Voces unidas, Colorado, Culture (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Latino press, Resources, newsclippings (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Raza contacts, Chicano publications, 1998 Chicano reunion (Box 143, Folder 4)
  - Latinos-L.A. Aug 29 (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Zephyr press, 1990 Chicano conference, Arizona Border rights, 25 years of La Clinica's history (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Wartime-COC, 1950's Chicanas, honors, South end press-editing (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Beyond Chicanismo, The symbols of resistance, La Seis de Boulder, OUSD (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - The struggle to La Sierra, Beyond Chicanismo, The symbol of resistance (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Rooted & rising, Notes, Chicanas + other latinas history/theory (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Lector, the Alhambra and the generalife, Seville, Colorlines, Corazon de Aztlan, La voz de pueblo, La voz de esperanza (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - California-environmental racism. N.M. environment, Pollution, EPA article, 25 years of la clinica's history, South west network (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Mexico Unam huelga Estudiantil, 2000 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - PLM + Talavera, Feminism, Mexican Revolution, Teresa Urrea, N.M.A state, Rich + poor, Women work entertain/ditules, Juaro Briones, Elena, Chipita (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Stop the lynchings, Escuelatas, Cruz Azul, Valentina Primer congreso, Las inovidables, Soldaderas, Jovita Idar, Tejera in Rev. (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Escuela Tlatel, Centro De la Raza, Brown Berets, National chicano youth conference, 1968 walkout! Chicana press (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Alicia Escalante, Life of a Campesino, Farmworkers, Dolores Huerta, Blood on the grapes, Two great hearts Artemisa + Luisa (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Curry + Cordova, Malcs, M. Melville, Sosa-Ridu, Falcon, Lopez + Uriarte, Castaneda + Apodaca, LRU, Floral workers strike, Marcha de la reconquesa, FLOC, Texas farmworkers (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Mela, Raza womyn L.A., His Panas unidas, Mujer latinas, Intro w. org. Mana (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Justice 4 Janitors, Mary Pardo, Pulido + Perquera, Latinos y que, Little village p. 177, Chicago communidad, MUA 12-3, NLHO 1 & 2 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Dorinda Moreno, Francisca Flores, Enriqueta Vasquez, Ananieto Gomez, Gracia Molina, Intro + Facio Broyles Castillo (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - No Vietnam, L.A Moratorium, Los Siete, Olgo I. Copper mine strike, La Lucha Obrera, Farah Strike, Watsonville strike, Casa 1 + 2, Vicki Mercado, Feminism-Intro, 1971 Chicano Conference (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Racism + youth, National chicano student conference 4/92, L.A-Chicano studies-clips, San Diego, 9/18-19/02, Latinisma group, Dinuba, Youth Activism 2000 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Teaching for change. Donna's letter and Maria Elena 1970-75, Video-leaflets, logo, NACCS-1998 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Cesar Chavez inst. Lef foundation (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - New Raza left-L.A. Chicanos left/analysis (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Correspondencia. La Corridinadora nacional del matimento urbano popular. El taco del sal. La organization revolucionaria punto critico apoyo la condidatura de cucuhtemoc carpenas. Lasa firum. La tuerca. "open borders". Poster (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Latinos for Jackson rainbow. Importance report and recent clips on immigration. (Part 1) (Box 100, Folder 3-4)
  - Proposal: the politics of place: the local left in America, revista de revistas. Para dicirle adios a Eduardo Silva: an anthology of poems teatro aguarcaro November, 1985, curriculum vita. Mexico journal. Tomorrow will be another day. Silence. Questions for author. (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Migra-Intro (Box 98, Folder 38)
  - Broyles Castillo (Box 98, Folder 36)
  - OSA (Box 98, Folder 35)
  - Aztec Hip Hop (Box 98, Folder 34)
  - Mansal/Alvarado (Box 98, Folder 33)
  - Adios 2 Danzantes (Box 98, Folder 32)
  - Minn. Daziza/GMA (Box 98, Folder 31)
  - White Hawk (Box 98, Folder 30)
  - Castro Xitlalli (Box 98, Folder 29)
  - Carmelo/Agudor (Box 98, Folder 28)
  - Cobb/Earthy (Box 98, Folder 27)
  - Ethnic Studies (Box 98, Folder 26)
  - Title Indigenismo (Box 98, Folder 25)
  - Intro + facio (Box 98, Folder 24)
  - Jovita Idar (Box 98, Folder 23)
  - Dorinda Morena (Box 98, Folders 21-22)
  - Enriqueta Vasquez (Box 98, Folder 20)
  - Gracia Molina de pick (Box 98, Folder 19)
  - Francisca Flores (Box 98, Folder 18)
  - National Chicano conference (Box 98, Folder 17)
  - Walkout! (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - Dolores Huerta (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Blood on the grapes (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - LRU-La raza unida (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Chicano Moratorium (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Los Siele (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Title page: the movement (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Marcha de la reconquista (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Watsonville (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Floral workers strike (Box 98, Folders 6-7)
  - Midwest 1 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Escuela Tlatelolco (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - More UFW (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Life of a farmworker (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Curanderas (Box 97, Folder 55)
  - Lesbianas (Box 97, Folder 54)
  - Texas Farmworkers (Box 97, Folder 53)
  - Map (Box 97, Folder 52)
  - Viva la Mujer! Cover page (Box 97, Folder 51)
  - Peace and dignity runs (Box 97, Folder 50)
  - Vicki Mercado (Box 97, Folder 49)
  - Las Hermanas (Box 97, Folder 48)
  - Intro-W.O. Mana (Box 97, Folder 47)
  - Mujeres Latinas (Box 97, Folder 46)
  - Latinas y que! (Box 97, Folder 45)
  - Day Laborers (Box 97, Folder 44)
  - Writers (Box 97, Folder 43)
  - Sacramento, 1994 (Box 97, Folder 42)
  - Hayward, 1994 (Box 97, Folder 41)
  - Barrio defense committee (Box 97, Folder 40)
  - Cobb+Izcalli (Box 97, Folder 39)
  - Intro-Danza (Box 97, Folder 38)
  - N.M Ganados+ cold (Box 97, Folder 37)
  - New York, east coast (Box 97, Folder 36)
  - Education-Intro (Box 97, Folder 35)
  - ICS-L.Angeles (Box 97, Folder 34)
  - Adios-4 Danzantes (Box 97, Folder 33)
  - Favi-fri (Box 97, Folder 32)
  - Luna/Mana Miranda (Box 97, Folder 31)
  - Folklorico (Box 97, Folder 30)
  - Tenaz (Box 97, Folder 29)
  - Teatro Campesino (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - Cherries M./Marisela (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - Beva/Tanderas (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - Integrate schools (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - Sylvia Morales (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Bakke Decision (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Schools not jails (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - NLHO-2 (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - FLOC (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - FLOC-new (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Marachi, Estrella (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Curry + Cordova (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Lopez, Uriarte (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Mary Pardo (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Castaneda, Facio (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Sosarido Falcon arobaca (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - SWU-revised (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Poder (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Mujer Obrera (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - NLHO-Health (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Radio (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Raza Womyn-L.A. (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Linda, Martha, Accordion (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Tex-Mex singer (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Ana Nieto-Gomez (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - "La Musica" intro (Box 96, Folder 43)
  - Mua (Box 96, Folder 42)
  - MALCS (Box 96, Folders 40-41)
  - Acknowledgments (Box 96, Folder 39)
  - M. Elena + coatligue (Box 96, Folder 38)
  - Lourdes Portillo (Box 96, Folder 37)
  - Elena (Box 96, Folder 36)
  - Carmen Tafolia (Box 96, Folder 35)
  - La virgen (Box 96, Folder 34)
  - Lopez & Romero (Box 96, Folder 33)
  - Counter insurgency (Box 96, Folder 32)
  - Conchord protest, 1998 (Box 96, Folder 31)
  - Cordova sisters (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - ODB, 2005-05-19 (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - Michigan (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Esperanza (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - 3 leaders for immigration (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - Caitan + Palacos (Box 96, Folder 25)
  - Protest grows (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - St. Peters housing (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - PCUN (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Fuerza unida (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - Fast 4 education (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - Justice 4 Jan (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - La colectiva de mujeres (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural workers (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Chicago communidad (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Mujer a mujer (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Health (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Juarez murders (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Floc victory (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - 3 Leaders (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - No 187 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Lideres campesinas (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Durazo (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Olga Talamante (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Remembering Chavez (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Little village (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Mela (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Las Chicanas (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Notes towards + strategy for Chicanos in S.W and N.M in particular, Rad (see also SWOP) beta west, LIF Article on SWOP, Watra court update, Mountain View (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Community empowered and Chicano scholarships, Census information kit, Invitation to Chicano studies, University of Notre Dame Press 1989, Fliers, Latinos Organizing (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Media alliance people behind the news, Speak their names by Loco Bloco writers (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Chicanos M. L. Words-songs, Permission into form (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Letters, Op ed #2- "Why we cant go back to Mexico," 11/20/97 Thanksgiving Juarez (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - PMP Latino Voices, Up Ed 5/96 for PMP, Foreward/growdy "Women writing resistance" (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Viva La Causa flyers, Old contact lists, Reader production/sale, Cinco De Mayo (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Centro Sin Fronteras, Discussion group (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Adobe, Tupac Amaru y los rebeldes de Peru, Justicia (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Laminas de La Raza (Box 168, Folder 2)
  - El Mestizo, Chicano student news, Speech Taos March 19, 1979, Armed creativity, July 25, 1977 a conversation with John Nichols, Adelte Campesino, Los Chicanos translation (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Chicano Newsprints, Urban life faced by La Raza, Publisher agreement, Letter permission for "Viva La Raza," The need for a Chicano independent party (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Personal papers of Antonio Cordero (Box 53, Folders 5-6)
  - Larry Trudillo photo Copy Negs + Proofs, Photos-Santa Barbara clips (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Xochitl Guerrero, Marga Gomez, Cherrie Moraga, Monica Palacius, Lomas Garza, Ester Hernandez (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Gloria Anzaldua, Avotcja, Ana Castillo, Ana C. Mariella (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Latinas, Arts, Avotcja, Poetry (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Yvonne Yarbro, Rebolledo (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Cardenas visits, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Immigration up to 1990 (Box 29, Folders 2-3)
  - Chicano Journalism, Chicano Labor, Chicanos and repression (including right wing) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Cesar Chavez (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Chicanos: education, Rudy A. Notes, Chicano-Indian relations (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Chicano history/culture/movement (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Chicano-General (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Kiko Martinez correspondence, David Alan Wayte, Chicanos-east bay (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Kiko Martinez case (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - CCAC community workshop: immigration, Fall, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Contemporary Latina lit (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Landscapes xeroxes, New Mexico: El Grito 1968-75, New Mexico review, Native American: Big Mountains, Safeway workers, Santa Fe workers 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chicano "Eyes on the Prize" (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Promo material part 2, Chicano "Eyes on the Prize" (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Promo material part 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Viva La Raza book, Letter of recomendation, Howard Zinn, Ted Vincent (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 6. El Grito del Norte
  Martinez was co-editor of this New Mexico magazine from 1968-1973.
  - El Grito del Norte book (Flat-box 169, Folder 2)
  - Short talk on origins of "El Grito," War times, pamphlet, Video permission forms (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - El Grito del Norte, Labor strike correspondence (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - The Mexican wars, Grito Del Norte (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - El Grito (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam 1972, El Grito 1968-1973, Beverly Axelrod (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - El Grito problems (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 7. Chicano Communications Center [CCC] / Chicano League Against Racism and Oppression [CLARO]
  Martinez was a co-founder of the Chicano Communications Center. CLARO was a CCC project with other groups.
  - C.L.A.R.O. (Flat-box 180, Folder 1)
  - C.L.A.R.O. Including purge (Flat-box 173, Folder 1)
  - C.L.A.R.O. outline for discussion study, 1975-10-05 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Chicano Communications Center, Letters, Tawani Wakawa Shoush 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 8. Institute for Multiracial Justice [IMJ]
  IMJ was co-founded by Martinez in 1997. According to their mission statement, the Institute is "committed to linking the struggle of Third World unity with struggles to build a new society free of class relations, sexism, homophobia, environmental abuse, and the other diseases of our times."
  - Institute for Multiracial Justice mailing list, Viva la Causa 8/13/09 account closed, Dissolution of institute (Box 161, Folder 2)
  - Institute for Multiracial Justice contacts, Immigrant rights + information, Mexico history, L. A 10/26-28 (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Pay history 2000, Reconciliation of checks (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - IMRJ application-Afifa Ahmed-extras, Board minutes, Pay histories 2001 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Institute for Multiracial Justice, Black Berets 2007, Susan Jones letter (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 9. Shades of Power [IMJ newsletter]
  - Color lines, Network news, Shades of Power (Box 160, Folder 4)
  - Shades of power, Filmakers library, War times, Women of color, Institute for Multiracial Justice, misc. papers (Box 161, Folder 1)
  - Colorlines, Shades of power (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Shades of power files (Box 125, Folders 2-4)
  - Bank statement, Shades of power, Master copies (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Discussion Guide for "Shades of Power", Institute for Multiracial Justice (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Charter of the U.N. Shades of Power newsletter (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Introduction to Welcome to Shades of Power and how to use it, Help build alliances, Discussion guide for "Shades of Power, articles (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Collection of articles, "Shades of power" (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Shades of Power, SNCC women anthology (Box 77, Folder 7)
- 10. Southwest Organizing Project [SWOP]
  SWOP publishes Martinez's Viva La Causa: 500 Years of Chicano History teaching kit.
  - SWOP Voces Unidas (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - SWOP general (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - Network news, Immigration, SWOP, 1990-1991 (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - SWOP, Raza history, Gangs (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - SWOP (Box 97, Folder 10)
- 11. Southwest Network for Environmental and Economic Justice [SNEEJ]
  - SNEEJ general, Environment, US land-N.M SNEEJ-2000-Nov 1-5, 2000-11 (Box 155, Folder 3)
  - SNEEJ-2000-10th gathering (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Docs from gathering 2nd annual, SNEEJ gathering 9/92, reports in the interfaith hearing on toxic poisoning in communist of color south west network (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - SNEEJ (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Southwest network for enviromental economic justice, Americas Civil right movement teaching package (Box 87, Folder 1)